Guide to the SFO Travel Ban Protest poster collection SC1346
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
SFO Travel Ban Protest poster collection
2017 Jan 28-29
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
SC1346
6 Linear Feet (2 flat boxes and 1 map folder)
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift, 2017.
Biographical / Historical
On January 27, 2017, President Donald Trump signed Executive Order 13769, titled “Protecting the Nation from Foreign Terrorist Entry into the United States.” The order lowered the number of refugees to be admitted into the United States in 2017 to 50,000, suspended the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program (USRAP) for 120 days, suspended the entry of Syrian refugees indefinitely, directed some cabinet secretaries to suspend entry of those whose countries do not meet adjudication standards under U.S. immigration law, and included exceptions on a case-by-case basis. Homeland Security lists these countries as Iran, Iraq, Libya, Somalia, Sudan, Syria, and Yemen.
Beginning on January 28 thousands of protesters gathered at airports and other locations throughout the United States to protest the signing of the order and detention of the foreign nationals.
Immediately, there were numerous protests and legal challenges. A nationwide temporary restraining order (TRO) was issued on February 3, 2017 in the case Washington v. Trump, which was upheld by the United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit on February 9, 2017. Consequently, the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) stopped enforcing portions of the order and the State Department re-validated visas that had been previously revoked.
Text from: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Executive_Order_13769
Scope and Contents
Posters from protests of Executive Order 13769 held at SFO on January 28-29, 2017.
Arrangement
Smaller posters are housed in 2 boxes; oversized posters are stored in map case.
Political posters, American.; Protest movements -- United States; Trump, Donald, 1946-
- Posters, Accession ARCH_2017_227
  - Immigrants make our country great, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - We were all immigrants once upon a time, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - Make Racists Afraid Again, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - We are all Immigrants Never Again, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - America Does not Ban, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - This Sanctuary City stands with Muslims, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - Immigrants are America, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - Fear Bad Decisions, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - No ban no wall sanctuary for all, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - Refugees welcome, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - Refugees are welcome here #no ban #no wall, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - Security Theater Creates a More Dangerous Reality, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - Congress Step Up, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - Muslim Ban lets take a stand, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - Really?, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - Food and water for all!, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - Refugees Welcome Here, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - Solidarity not Bigotry #stop the ban, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - My family fled Vietnam on Boats US Saved them, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - Another Jew against the Muslim Ban, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - Not on Our Watch, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - No Ban. No Wall., 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - Water and food for all, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - #Not In our name Stop the #Muslim Ban, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - Trump is Anti-America, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - Immigrants make America great, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - Not in our name Let them In!, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - Give us your poor, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - #Not In our name Stop the #Muslim Ban, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - Exclusion = Un-American, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - Welcoming All makes us Great, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 1)
  - Refugees are welcome here, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 2)
  - No Ban, No Wall, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 2)
  - If you're not angry you're not listening, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 2)
  - No Ban, No Wall, We'll fight them All, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 2)
  - Trump is Not America Refugees and Immigrants Welcome, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 2)
  - Free Refugees now, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 2)
  - We're not the United States of Breitbart, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 2)
  - Refugees Welcome Here, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 2)
  - Not in my name, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 2)
  - No Ban No Wall, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 2)
  - Immigrants and their Children Built America, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 2)
  - No Human Being Is Illegal, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Box 2)
  - Muslim Ban UnAmerican, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Map-folder 3)
  - Fascist Endings R Not Pretty, 2017 Jan 28-29 (Map-folder 3)